balfour.com 2018-06-17

# Balfour :: Privacy & Security - Legal - About Us | Balfour

**PRIVACY POLICY**

We at American Achievement Corporation (“AAC,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) have created this privacy policy (this “Privacy Policy”) because we know that you care about how information you provide to us is used and shared.  This Privacy Policy applies to information collected when you visit any of our websites, which include, without limitation, <http://www.balfour.com/> and <http://www.artcarved.com/> (the “Websites”), access our mobile app, which may be accessible through mobile devices and tablets (the “Mobile App”), access and use our services provided through the Websites and the Mobile App (“Services”), or purchase our products (“Products”).  The Websites and the Mobile App are collectively referred to as the “Online and Digital Properties.”

**_Acceptance of Terms_**

By visiting our Websites, accessing our Mobile App, accessing and using our Services, and/or purchasing our Products, you are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the accompanying Terms of Use.  Capitalized terms not defined in this Privacy Policy shall have the meaning set forth in the Terms of Use.

**_What Information We Collect/Receive_**

We collect and/or receive the following categories of information:

**_Contact Information_**

When you contact us through the “Contact Us” page, or sign up to receive special offers & promotions, or sign up to become a Registered User, you will be asked to provide certain information which may include your name, e-mail address, phone number, and student’s name if you are registering on behalf of a student (collectively, the “Contact Information”).

If you sign in using your Facebook or any other social media account, you are authorizing AAC to collect, store, and use, in accordance with this Privacy Policy, any and all information that you agreed that Facebook, Inc., or such other social media company could provide to AAC through its Application Programming Interface. Such information may include, without limitation, your first and last name, username, profile picture, unique social media identifier and access token, and e-mail address.

**_Billing Information_**

In order to submit orders through the Online and Digital Properties you will be required to provide certain information in addition to the Contact Information noted above.  Such information may include PayPal, Payflow account information, debit card number, credit card number, billing address, and similar information (collectively, the “Billing Information).  For orders submitted through the Online and Digital Properties, the Billing Information is collected, stored and processed by our third-party payment vendors pursuant to the terms and conditions of their privacy policies and terms of use.

You may also submit orders by using our paper order forms. If you submit orders using our paper order forms, you will be required to fill in the Billing Information on our paper forms. Once we receive your paper order forms, our customer service representatives will enter your Billing Information through our Websites in order to allow our third-party payment vendors to collect, store and process such information pursuant to the terms and conditions of their privacy policies and terms of use. All paper order forms are also scanned by our third-party service providers into encrypted files which are stored on our servers. The encrypted files do not contain the Billing Information. We also store your original paper order forms in locked cabinets until your order is processed. Once your order is processed, your original paper order forms are destroyed.

**_Order Information_**

If you wish to purchase our Products, you will also be required to provide us with certain additional information such as your name, shipping address, and the Products you wish to order (“Order Information”).  If you place an order as a guest (without creating an account as a Registered User), we will use your Order Information solely as necessary to process your order.

**_Geolocational Information_**

Certain features and functionalities of the Online and Digital Properties are based on your location.  In order to provide these features and functionalities while you are using a mobile device, we may, with your consent, automatically collect geolocational information from your mobile device or wireless carrier and/or certain third-party service providers.  Such information is collectively called the “Geolocational Information.” Collection of Geolocational Information occurs only when the Mobile App is running on your mobile device. You may decline to allow us to collect such Geolocational Information, in which case we will not be able to provide certain features of the Mobile App to you.

**_Other Information_**

In addition to the Contact Information, Order Information, and Geolocational Information we may collect and/or receive additional information (collectively, the “ _Other Information_ ”).  Such Other Information may include:

  * **_From your Activity.       _**In an ongoing effort to improve our Online and Digital Properties, we automatically collect certain information when visitors visit the Websites and Registered Users use the Online and Digital Properties, such as your IP addresses, browser type and language, referring and exit pages and URLs, date and time, amount of time spent on particular pages, what sections of the Websites visitors visit, similar information concerning your use of the Online and Digital Properties, information about a mobile device, including universally unique ID (“UUID”), App type and version (e.g., iOS or Android), carrier and country location, hardware and processor information (storage, chip speed, camera resolution, NFC enabled, and network type (WiFi, 2G, 3G, 4G). If you use the “Shop Your School” feature on the Online and Digital Properties, we will collect the zip code that you use to use this feature, together with your IP address and school information. ** _ _**

  * **From Cookies.**        We may use both session cookies, which expire once you close your web browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your computer until you delete them and other technologies to help us collect data and to enhance your experience with the Online and Digital Properties.  Cookies are small text files a website can use to recognize a repeat visitor to the website.  We may use cookies for various purposes, including to authenticate users, personalize your experience, analyze which portions of the Online and Digital Properties are visited most frequently, and measure and optimize advertising and promotional effectiveness. If you do not want us to deploy cookies in your browser, you can opt out by setting your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when a website tries to put a cookie in your browser software.  If you choose to disable cookies in your browser, you can still use the Online and Digital Properties, although your ability to use some of the features may be affected.

  * **Third-Party Analytics.**        We also use third-party analytics services to evaluate your use of the Online and Digital Properties, compile reports on activity, collect demographic data, analyze performance metrics, and collect and evaluate other information relating to the Online and Digital Properties and Internet usage.  These third parties use cookies and other technologies to help analyze and provide us the data.  By accessing and using the Online and Digital Properties, you consent to the processing of data about you by these analytics providers in the manner and for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.  For more information on these third parties, including how to opt out from certain data collection, please visit the sites below.

  * For Google Analytics, please visit <https://www.google.com/analytics>
  * For Magento, please visit <https://magento.com/legal/terms/privacy>
  * For Crazy Egg, please visit <https://www.crazyegg.com/>

** ** ** _The Information Collected/Received from Your School_**

We may receive certain information about you from your school. Such information may include your name, and the Products you would like to order (“School Provided Information”). The School Provided Information shall be provided by your school in accordance with all applicable laws, including but not limited to Family Education and Privacy Act (“FERPA”),

**_The Information Collected/Received from our Sales Representatives and Through Paper Order Forms_**

We may receive your Contact Information, Billing Information and Order Information if you place your order with our sales representatives and/or using our paper order forms.

**_The Information Collected by or Through Third-Party Companies_**

We may share Other Information about you with third parties, including but not limited to, advertising companies, and our brand partners, for ad distribution and ad optimization (defined as the tailoring, targeting (i.e., behavioral, contextual, and retargeting), analyzing, managing, reporting, and optimizing of ads).  These third parties may use cookies, pixel tags (also called web beacons or clear gifs), and/or other technologies to collect Other Information for such purposes.  Pixel tags enable us and these third-party advertising companies to recognize a browser’s cookie when a browser visits the site on which the pixel tag is located in order to learn which advertisement brings a user to a given site.  In addition, we may receive Other Information from advertisers, brand partners, and/or their service providers such as advertising identifiers, IP addresses, and post-conversion data.

**_How to Opt Out of Third-Party Interest-Based Advertising_**

If you wish to opt out of third-party interest-based advertising, please visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) and [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) for details on how to do so.

**_How the Information is Shared   _**

You authorize us to use your Contact Information, Order Information, Geolocational Information, School Provided Information and Other Information (collectively, the “Information”) to provide and improve our Online and Digital Properties, Services and Products, to fulfill your requests and purchases; to send order notifications and marketing communications, to provide personalized and more convenient onsite shopping experience, to solicit your feedback, to inform you about our products and services and those of our promotional partners.  We will use your phone number to send you updates about your order and marketing notifications via SMS. If you would like to opt-out of receiving such SMS, please contact us at [privacy@artcarved.com](mailto:privacy@artcarved.com) and/or [privacy@balfour.com](mailto:privacy@balfour.com).

You also authorize us to use and/or share Information as described below.

  * We may employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples may include providing technical assistance, customer service, marketing assistance, billing, and administration of our promotional programs.  These other companies will have access to the Information only as necessary to perform their functions and to the extent permitted by law.

  * In an ongoing effort to better understand our users, the Online and Digital Properties, and our Products and Services, we may analyze your Information in anonymized and aggregate form in order to operate, maintain, manage, and improve the Online and Digital Properties and/or such Products and Services. This aggregate information does not identify you personally. We may share this aggregate data with our affiliates, agents, business and promotional partners, and other third parties. We may also disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe the Online and Digital Properties and our products and services to current and prospective business partners and investors and to other third parties for other lawful purposes.

  * We may share some or all of your Information with any of our parent companies, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control with us.

  * As we develop our businesses, we might sell or buy businesses or assets.  In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, sale of assets, dissolution, or similar event, the Information may be part of the transferred assets.

  * To the extent permitted by law, we may also disclose the Information: (i) when required by law, court order, or other government or law enforcement authority or regulatory agency; or (ii) whenever we believe that disclosing such Information is necessary or advisable, for example, to protect the rights, property, or safety of AAC or others.

We may share your Contact Information and Order Information with your school to determine your eligibility to receive the Products you order.

We may share your Contact Information, Order Information and School Provided Information with our sales representatives. All our sales representatives will use your information in accordance with the agreements we have with the sales representatives and solely as necessary to provide our Products and Services to you.

We may also share your credit card information in an anonymized manner with our business partners to create profiles to help us better market to our users.

We may share your Contact Information with your school counselors who will use the information to message you about your order.

**_Information we may Contribute to Cooperative Databases_**

We may contribute your Information to cooperative databases which give third parties subscribing for such databases access to your Information for the purposes of confirming viability of e-mails and fraud protection. If you do not wish to have your Information contributed to cooperative databases, please send an e-mail to [privacy@artcarved.com](mailto:privacy@artcarved.com) and/or [privacy@balfour.com](mailto:privacy@balfour.com).

**_Accessing and Modifying Information and Communication Preferences_**

If you have provided us any Contact Information and/or Order Information, you may access, remove, review, and/or make changes to certain elements of the same by logging in to your account.  In addition, you may manage your receipt of marketing and non-transactional communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of any AAC marketing e-mail.  We will use commercially reasonable efforts to process such requests in a timely manner.  You should be aware, however, that it is not always possible to completely remove or modify information in our subscription databases.  You cannot opt out of receiving transactional e-mails related to the Online and Digital Properties.

**_How We Protect Your Information_**

We take commercially reasonable steps to protect the Information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.  Please understand, however, that no security system is impenetrable.  We cannot guarantee the security of our databases or the databases of the third parties with which we may share such Information, nor can we guarantee that the Information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted over the Internet.  If you send us an email, we cannot guarantee the security of any information contained therein because we do not have control over the security of incoming emails.

**_Important Notices to Non-U.S. Residents_**

The Online and Digital Properties and its servers are operated in the United States and elsewhere.   Please be aware that your Information may be transferred to, processed, maintained, and used on computers, servers, and systems located outside of your state, province, country, or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your country of origin.  If you are located outside the United States and choose to use the Online and Digital Properties, you do so at your own risk.

If (1) you wish to opt out; or (2) you wish to request certain information regarding our disclosure of your personal information to third parties for the direct marketing purposes, please send an e-mail to privacy@artcarved.com and/or privacy@balfour.com with “Privacy Policy” in the subject line or write to us at:

American Achievement Corporation  
1550 W Mockingbird Lane  
Dallas, Texas 75235

**_External Websites_**

The Online and Digital Properties may contain links to third-party websites. (“External Sites”)  AAC has no control over the privacy practices or the content of these External Sites.  As such, we are not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of these External Sites. You should check the applicable third-party privacy policy and terms of use when visiting any such External Sites.

**_Children_**

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.  If you are under 13, please do not give us any personal information.  We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce our Privacy Policy by instructing their children to never provide personal information without their permission.  If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided personal information to us, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete that information from our databases.

**_California Residents_**

Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, California residents who have an established business relationship with AAC may choose to opt out of our sharing your personal information with third parties for direct marketing purposes.  If you are a California resident and (1) you wish to opt out; or (2) you wish to request certain information regarding our disclosure of your personal information to third parties for the direct marketing purposes, please send an e-mail to [privacy@artcarved.com](mailto:privacy@artcarved.com) and/or [privacy@balfour.com](mailto:privacy@balfour.com) with “Privacy Policy” in the subject line or write to us at:

American Achievement Corporation  
1550 W Mockingbird Lane  
Dallas, Texas 75235

In addition, AAC does not monitor, recognize, or honor any opt-out or do not track mechanisms, including general web browser “Do Not Track” settings and/or signals.

**_Changes to This Privacy Policy_**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of the date stated at the top of this Privacy Policy.  We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time.  Any such changes will be posted on the Online and Digital Properties.  By accessing the Online and Digital Properties, accessing our Services, and/or ordering our Products after we make any such changes to this Privacy Policy, you are deemed to have accepted such changes.  Please be aware that, to the extent permitted by applicable law, our use of the Information is governed by the Privacy Policy in effect at the time we collect the Information.  Please refer back to this Privacy Policy on a regular basis.

**_How to Contact Us_**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us in one of the following ways:

Email: [privacy@balfour.com](mailto:privacy@balfour.com) and/or [privacy@artcarved.com](mailto:privacy@artcarved.com)

Phone: 1-800-BALFOUR

Or write to us at:

American Achievement Corporation  
1550 W Mockingbird Lane  
Dallas, Texas 75235
